No Nelson to create our first project.
And there is that tradition, additional programming that our first program should be to output the
text, tell over to the console, and this is what we're going to do in this video.
Therefore, I'm going to open intelligent.
You should open until a JDAM.
On the latest.
I make sure we have projects selected and click on this plus button to create a new project.
And here we have a few options.
The first is the name and he'll need to name our project.
We need to give a name to our project and the name of the project.
We started a capital letter and if it has multiple words, every word for starts with a capital letter.
So I'm going to call this on on this new way of naming is called the Pascal case.
So I'm going to call this this project Hello world and also if should not have white spaces in your
name.
Next we have the location and this is where the project is going to be created.
You can change this location if you want, but I'm going to keep the default location.
Next, we have language and here you here do need to select the language on which this project is going
to be created.
So we select Kotlin.
If you're Java selected your selection for the B system, we select intelligent and next we have the
JDK, the Java development kit.
And if for whatever reason it says here in angled brackets and the decay, just click on that and go
down here or down off to often it will say detect the G case and you will see the JDK down there.
You're going to see Amazon quoted over version 17.
Just click on that.
It's going to be added here.
Next, we have this odd the sample code and what this is going to do, as the name implies, is going
to generate some code for us.
But I don't want it to have that code generated now because I want to type that code myself and I want
to explain that code.
And in the next video, we're going to check that to generate the code for us.
So I'm going to click on Create the Now to create the project.
And here you have the teams who can keep that you activated because it's a useful information.
But I'm going to check this.
Actually, I'm going to just close it.
You have those windows which is that is that is a plug in update installed.
I'm going to close this.
So what we have now on the left hand side is called the Project Pane, and here we have song folders
which intelligent idea generated for us.
But now I want to I want to show you how to check for intelligent updates, because in this way, we'll
have the latest features throughout this course.
And to check for intelligent data, go to help and to go down here to research, check for updates.
And here you can check for intelligent dates and you will see a window down here.
And if there is an update, is going to say that there is an update and can install that update.
But now we're saying that that you already have the latest version of intelligent plugins installed
because we have the latest updates, but is good to check for this because in this way we'll have the
latest updates throughout this course.
Next check if you want to check for Kotlin updates or for the programming language you Kotlin, you
go to tools Kotlin and go here it is.
Configure Kotlin plugin updates and if there is a new update, you will see it here and click on installing.
That update is going to be installed on Intel.
Jerry So there is no update because we have the latest update I'm going to click on.
Okay.
Now let's focus on the left hand side and if you don't see it, if you see something like this and you
don't see this in this expanded font, just click on this greater sign sign in front of Sara Caesar
assistance for source.
This is what our source code is going to go.
Then click on this greater sign in front of Man and make sure to have the folder Kotlin selected on
this folder.
Kotlin This is what's going to hold our code.
But first we need to create the file, and the file is the theme.
We're going to put our code so we right click on this, go to your and here we select on the right hand
side to select coddling class file.
Now we need to give an entire file and I'm going to call this file main.
You will see the reason for this later.
So I'm going to call this for File Main.
The name also should be in Pascal.
Okay, so we should start with the capital letter.
Even if it has multiple arrows, every word is for subs, the capital capitalism and for the from this
options that we have here, we select file because we're going to create others in the file now press
enter.
Now, the file was created for us as it goes in the folder.
CAITLYN No, we have meant that you have the file, and also it opened the file for us.
So let's.
Click there.
Now, if you don't have the file open and if you only have something like this, just double click on
the file in the file is going to be open for, you know, hit it.
Now we're going to type song called now you need to type exactly what I type so type fun.
So while I am typing, as you can see, A.J. is trying to help us and is given us some suggestions.
So you're saying do mean fun?
That and if you want to fill in that what we just présenter because I want you to type that fun keyword
fun.
And we also added the space.
So fun space then what?
I mean.
And next we need to put parenthesis.
And as you can see, this play button now appeared.
I'm going to explain immediately why.
And we put the left parameters.
And when we put the left is the right parent is going to be added automatically.
So we pause to let parents and the right parents without the automatically.
Then we get outside of the parenthesis, we put a space.
Now we're going to add curly braces.
And again, who put the left calibration that I calibrate is going to be added automatically, because
A.J. is helping us know we would inside the calibrations and now we press enter and it added the curly
brace on the third line and also indented this line for us.
Now, let's talk about what we have here.
Now, what we have here is we what we use what is called the main function.
And the main function is the entry point of our program.
So every program that you create it, if it first needs this entry point in order to be able to compile
your code.
But let's take each part of this main function individually to talk about.
So first we have this fun, and fun is the keyword for creating a function.
And you can use this function to create your own functions, but you're going to see that in and future
videos.
Next to have main a main is the name of this function.
Functions can have different names, but Main is a special one, as I said, because Main is the entry
point of our program.
Maybe every program that you create needs and it needs a main function in order to be able to run your
code.
And in fact, if I change the name of this function to Fun Main, let's say A the playback button immediately
disappeared because now we don't have an entry point and our programming cannot run.
So this special function and functions can have different rating names, as I said, and as you will
see when you're going to create your own function that you can create, you can give the different names
to other functions.
Now, next, we have parentheses and we have parentheses because functions can take parameters and can
do some work without those parameters.
But our function does not take any parameter, but we still need to provide the parentheses because
they are part of the syntax and we can think of the syntax like the grammar rules that we need to do
to respect in a specific language in order to be to be a order to be understood.
To be understood.
And in the same way, this is the syntax in the programming set.
It's like the grammar rules in which the compiler, as you will see, what is the compiler later, the
compiler needs to enforce as you to respect those syntactical rules, which is to have parentheses for
a function in order to be able to understand your code.
Because if I delete the parentheses here, now have an underline which says expecting parentheses.
So it's it it you need to respect the syntactical rules in order for your code to be to be understood
next to have curly braces.
And we have left curly brace and dry turtle base and this is called the body of the function.
So this is what our code goes.
So this is also called the code block because it's the block of code.
This is what our logic, our our this what our logical lines of code go down.
We define them inside the and the the curly braces.
So this represents the body of the function and let's out some code and I'm going to type it into line
here.
So because we need to output something in the console so we type here the print line, so we type print
and well and dumping you.
So she has suggested and we have the suggestion print line and we select the first one to fill in for
us.
And now we go inside the parenthesis of the print line and we put double quotation marks and inside
the double quotation marks we type Hello.
World.
Now we need to.
We need to run this code.
And in order to run this code to compile the squad, we can do it in two ways.
First, you can click on this play button that we have here.
Or you can right click and you can go here where it says Run, meaning that getting the quote is going
to be compiled.
And let's do it from here.
First, I'm going to click on this play button to run our code, and I'm going to see the console opening
down and you're going to see the text.
Hello world had a word, output it.
So the console opened and we have hello world.
We have the text that we type inside this thing that we have here.
This is also a function and to have this code outputs it and now in the console the console opened.
Now I'm going to I'm going to close the console to explain what this print line is.
This print line that we have here is a function also.
But is that the function which takes some it which takes input and the input is this sticks and this
function, the its job is to take whatever you pass as the input and to output that in the console.
So this is what this print line is doing and this is a function that we didn't create, we didn't type
free were fun print line and then we call it this function which is built into quantity.
And this is a fact which is already built by the Kotlin programmers.
So we just call that function inside our code.
And can you as you don't need to create this function.
So this is the this is what this print line is doing.
So it's taken whatever you pass inside the parentheses and it's outputting that in the console.
So this is our discussion about the first program, which is to output some takes and the console helloworld.
And now I'm going to show you that I now I'm going to show you an illustration to understand what is
what is the JDK, the JVM and how Kotlin and Java achieves this interoperability because Kotlin and
Java are fully interoperable.
And that means that you can you can have a Java project to which you can add quoted in code and you
can compile that code and everything will work fine.
And also, I'm going to play in order what the word compiler means.
And for that I'm going to bring early in and here.
So this is the illustration.
And let's talk about what we have here.
First, we have Kotlin source code and Kotlin source code is the code that we wrote is this code that
is meant to be human readable.
So this code is the code that we as humans can understand.
We can write this code, we can read this God.
But the computer does understand this high level, high level code that we wrote.
It needs something.
It's need it needs machine quote, it needs binary code in order to be able to understand.
And this is where the JDK comes into action.
So our Kotlin source code, again, this quad, which is meant to be human readable, then it when when
we press on that below play button one and when you press on that play button on this button and the
code is compiled, what happens under the hood is that that Kotlin source code is, is taken by the
Java development kit, the JDK and through the Kotlin compiler.
So the controlling compiler acts like a translator.
It takes that high level human readable and writable code.
It converts that code then into what is called Java bytecode.
And this is not the final step, as you can see in this illustration, just this is just the intermediary
step.
This is not converted into a machine code.
Then this Java byte code, it's taken by the Java.
And so it's send to the JVM and the JVM then takes that Java bytecode and convert the general Java bytecode
into something which a machine, which our specific machine can understand.
But let's, let's first explain why, why.
Kotlin Wired The JDK text is quoted in source code, and then it converted its Scotland source code
into the Java bytecode.
And this is doing this because different processors and different operating systems need different instructions
in order to understand our code.
So if we are not, will not to have this Java bytecode.
So if we had, we will compile our code on a specific platform.
That code can run only on that specific platform, but because our source code is taken by the JDK and
through the computer and is converted into Java bytecode and the Java Byte code, then it's, it's it,
send it to the JVM and JVM stands for Java Virtual Machine and the JVM then because different platforms
and different operating a different browser and different processor needs the different instructions.
The JVM is the one which is doing the hard work with all figured out, figuring out what kind of instruction
that specific platform needs.
So it converts the Java bytecode into machine code, let's say, which is a Windows platform can understand.
Then the same thing happens to Linux that the JVM received the same Java byte code and then it converts
that Java by according to machine code, which a Linux platform can understand and then is doing the
same thing.
To a mac OS.
So the MC waves, the JVM is going to is going to receive the same Java bytecode and is going to convert
that Java bytecode into machine code which market makers can understand.
So this is how a quarter in Java can achieve this goal, this thing called write once and run everywhere.
This is because the the work of converting that machine code, which, which is a specific platform
I can understand, has shifted from the programmer to the platform which has the which implements that
JVM.
So we just wrote our code, we run our code to the JDK, the JDK converted that code in Java bytecode,
and then the platform which has the JVM installed is doing the work of converting that Java bytecode
that we wrote into something which that platform, that specific platform can understand.
So and this is why Java and Kotlin are fully interoperable.
So you can add the core, you cannot Java code to an existing Kotlin program and vice versa.
You cannot the you cannot the Java.
You cannot do quarterly in code to an existing Java program.
And that is that is possible because the JDK is going to is going to convert to the compiler all of
that code into the same Java bytecode.
And then that code is going to be run on the JVM and the JVM is going to convert that into machine code
and that code is going to run it on a specific platform.
So this is how Java and Kotlin and this is why Java and Quotidien online are fully interoperable because
they are they are ultimately converted into the same Java bytecode.
And you can also achieve this right once run everywhere because that code then runs on the JVM Java
virtual machine, which is doing the hard the long record of figuring out what kind of instructions
a specific platform needs in order to understand that code that we wrote.
And in this way that hard working has shifted from us to the people who implement the JVM.
So this how the JDK and the JVM also Under-the-hood.
And if you find this confusing, don't build this.
This is just a relaxed discussion about how the JDK, what is the JDK and what is the Kotlin compiler?
Because we said our code.
I said previously that our code is compiled.
When I said that, this was actually what was happening.
Our code was taken by the JDK and the JDK was go in Java bytecode and then it was sent to the JVM of
which is one of my windows, and then that is converted into machine code and then we see in the output
helloworld so this our discussion about the first program, how to get it, I had a word and this is
the additional discussion about how the JDK, how the coding compiler and how the JVM works.
So see in the next video.