So in the previous video we created our first program and even though it was a simple program, you
should celebrate because you created your first program.
But if you want to make a program to do something useful, you need to store data.
And in order to store data, you need to use variables.
And this is what we're going to talk about in this video.
Therefore, I'm going to open intelligent.
I'm going to create a new project, so make sure to that.
On the left hand side, you have probably selected click on this plus button to create the new project.
I'm going to call it variables.
It should be in Pascal case if it has multiple.
What is the language we have already causally selected for the belief system?
Intelligent and also make sure to have the key selected here and now I'm going to check this out.
Simple code because this is going to generate the code that we type previously respectively, the main
function and the print line two and the hell our text is going to be now auto generated for us.
Why?
Because we check this box on simple code and it is going to add the code automatically for us.
So I'm going to click on Create.
Now our project is ready to go.
And as you can see here, it generated song called for us and this is similar to what we did in the
previous video where we created our will, create our code ourselves.
But we have some additional code and I'm going to delete this additional code because it will make things
confusing.
So I'm going to delete this part.
Sorry, I'm going to do this part.
And also you may, may have noticed that, uh, here in, uh, inside this parenthesis now we have this
obtuse array and a string.
We can delete this too, because, uh, it'll, uh, making things confusing.
And we're going to talk about, uh, what are, uh, rays and all of that in the next videos.
Now I'm going to.
Alright.
Noted.
Now let's run this code to see.
To see what is happening is going to output.
Uh, that takes two like, uh, it did in the previous video.
You should open the console in a short moment and indeed it open the console and output to the text
hello world like it did in the previous video.
So I'm going to close the console now.
Also, let's expand this s r c to see the file that it was created automatically for us this time and.
Let's change this helo, what it takes to put into another place, let's say let's put into type your
name there.
And my case is Alex.
So I'm going to run this squad and it will output my name in the console.
All right, so it put it.
Hello, Alex.
Like we typed here.
But, um, it's, uh.
What we have here is pretty.
Pretty flexible.
It's a better way to, to to do that.
You to be.
To have something to store this name.
And then it is fair that that thing here to call that thing here in this world to be a bit more, um,
what do they know dynamic.
And to do that we need to use variables.
And variables are, um, unlike some containers which can hold data values and um.
Let's see how to create the variable.
Okay.
Let's, uh, put to the, uh, the code below the above our print, uh, allowance statement.
And um, if you don't know what a statement is, a statement is of complete, uh, instruction of execution.
Now, to create a variable, we just type the keyword var.
Which stands for variable.
All right.
Next, we need to give a name to our very own variable to be able to refer it later, to call it later.
And I'm going to earn the naming convention around naming.
The variable is column is called camel case.
And that means that the first the.
Letter in the name if it has multiple words.
So start with the lowercase letter.
So I'm going to type user and the next word name with the capital letter.
Alright.
The next I need to provide the type, type of the variable and that means what kind of data this variable
is going to hold is going to store.
To do that we need to put column in next we need to say what type of data is going to stored what?
What that does going to store.
And we want to store text and to store text.
We need to type here.
String and string means that this variable is going to store a a sequence of characters or text.
Now we need to assign a value to this variable and to do that to put we put here equals.
Space.
And because we explicitly said here that we weren't going to put these text or string, we put a double
pair of quotation marks and when we type.
Alex Alright, so now we create our variable.
We give it a name, a type, and we also assign a value is a variable.
Next we need to refer this variable down here and to, to, to refer to that variable.
I'm going to delete this text first and to refer the variable we put dollar sign.
And after the dollar sign, we start typing the name of the the variable user.
And as I'm typing, the intelligence is given us some suggestions.
And he said, do you mean this username variable?
And it also has this V here for a variable.
So I'm going to press enter to fill in that for me.
And if I.
Run the squad.
You'll see the exact.
Things are happening here.
It outputted the text to panelists, but this time we didn't type the text directly here.
We we we stored the text in a variable and we call that variable in, in our println.
I'm going to add a space here to make things more clear.
Now, what we can do is to change the value of this variable by.
Um.
Adding uh below for our variable.
Typing the name of the variable again user name equals.
And now we can assign a new value to this variable.
And let's put.
Let's put John here.
Right.
Let's run this code to see what happens now.
Now, this time, when this, uh.
This instruction is going to be called.
Is going to print, then the new value of the variable, which is John.
So as you can see down here, it outputs the text.
Hello, John.
So we can change the value of the variable after we assign a value to it.
But what you can't do is to is to type here username equals five and if you hover over here it says
integer literal does not conform to this painting type string and in other words is saying that we said
explicitly, explicitly up here that is going to store only text and down here we try to put a whole
number, an integer and that is not going to water because Kotlin is a length language which is which
is called statically typed.
And that means that it will check the types of the variable at compile time, not at runtime.
And that means it does it.
You cannot run your code if you assign a value to to a variable which has a different type done than
the type that you specify specified when you declare the variable.
This is why you get this warning here.
And if I delete this.
Now.
Listen to this.
All right.
Okay.
The next type of variable that were also actually not ordinate then is type David over.
The next way of declaring a variable is using the keyword file.
So if it declared it, if it declared a variable as Val, Val means that we cannot change its value
after we assign a value to it.
So if you try if you try to assign a new value to our variable like we did here, up here, it will
not work.
So let's actually let's actually just change here.
Let's put Val.
Okay.
And in after I did that, it immediately underlined in red the username and it says Val cannot be reassigned.
And that is because if it declared it, if declared a variable as val, you cannot change its value
later until you can put over a value to that variable only once.
And that's what we cannot change the variable, the value of the variable later.
So let's change back to Var to have the ability to change the value.
Now let's look at another type of variable.
So I'm going to type var again.
I'm going to call it age.
I'm going to put Colon to specify a type here.
And now we're going to use another type, which is int and instance for integer or for whole numbers.
Now I need to assign a value to it.
I'm going to call I'm going to put ten or 20, 22.
All right.
So what to have now is a different type.
Up here we have string.
And that means that we're going to we're going to store a sequence of characters.
And down here we have integers.
And that means that we can store only only numbers, only hold numbers.
And there are different type of numbers which are going to look in the next video.
And if I try here to change this.
Two changes first.
First, let's.
Let's actually.
Let's actually print this.
Uh, hello, Alex.
Let's type your age is in here to put dollar sign in we call the name of the variable we tied the name
of it's a variable age so you press enter to fill in that for us and if you run this squad.
No says hello, John.
Your age is 22, so it's No.
Two using the value, the values of this variable in our println and we can change for the variable
also the its value because is declared as a var not a value.
So we can put here age equals let's say 25 and if around this code.
The change is reflected immediately in our code.
So now you see.
Hello, John.
Your age is 25.
What we can do, like in the previous example with the username hit, we cannot put a string.
We cannot put hit Alex because we said explicitly here that this is going to is going to hold only integers,
only whole numbers.
So I'm going to delete this.
Let's put it again to 25 and the arrow error disappeared.
Alright, now let's look at what we have here because you have this underlines this great light out
of four types and every time you see something like this that means that intelligence trying to say
something to you and if you hover over here.
Actually it's hover over all over the type.
It says explicitly given type.
It's redundant here.
And that means that it does not need to.
We don't know.
We don't need to say explicitly here that is going to hold a sequence of characters, is going to hold
string because it knows this.
You can because it's quoted in has something which is called type in inference and that means that it
can infer the type of the variable by the value we assign to it.
In our case, we assign some.
So if I delete the type here
now.
It's still working.
And if I as you can see, if I if I put here if let's say if I try to put your username.
So username.
Equals two.
Three is still treated as a string because it in to it in further type by the value you assign to it.
And similar to this.
This thing applies to power in two types.
So if I delete this is still working, is still sitting, is still treating this as it.
Ozanian So if you try to pause here, edge equals to text and then all again we have this error and
if this is type mismatch if required int and found string and that means that it's still a.
It's still treating this, uh, variable as an end because as I said, it has something which is called
type inference and it can infer the type of the variable by the value assigned to it.
All right.
This is our discussion about variables that are more types of variables.
And we're going to look at that other types in the next two videos.
And collectively, they are called data types.
Okay.
You can remove this space if you want.
So I'm going to add this video now and see you in the next video.